<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jess Klein is a maker</title>
    <link>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jess Klein is a maker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackasaurus</title>
      <link>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/project/hackasaurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/project/hackasaurus/</guid>
      <description>Challenge It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to ask teens to go into sandbox environments to learn how to edit the Web.
Engagement strategy Run hack-jams with the New York and Chicago Public Libraries to user test how might we design web development learning experiences that meet youth where they are on the Web.
Design strategy Help teens remix the websites that they regularly with a bookmarklet. Teach the educators who support youth hackers so that they can be involved in the learning activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Design Kit</title>
      <link>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/project/odk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/project/odk/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Working openly with distributed teams can be complicated.
Engagement strategy Stage a few interventions with different kinds of teams to try to uncover practices and challenges unique to this specific kind of design.
Design strategy Provide tools to practitioners collaborating in distributed environments.
Solution Create a toolkit of methods (Open Design Kit) so that anyone: practitioners, clients, and collaborators can learn how to be productive and happy in this kind of collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockaway</title>
      <link>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/project/rockaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toolness.github.io/jess-portfolio/project/rockaway/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Local residents of the superstorm Sandy affected community in Rockaway Beach, NY want to be involved in rebuilding - by helping themselves
Engagement strategy Co-create hack jams,learning labs, and, prototype rebuilding opportunities.
Design strategy Uplevel prototypes to create emergency preparedness tools.
Solution Create a crisis response system that builds on top of existing technology used by community based, grassroot and established relief organizations to streamline communications and leverage data in order to develop a peer recognition system that can be used as part of an Emergency Response Kit for cities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>